

Andre Francavilla

Nationality: American, Italian

(+39) 3249810669

Date of birth: 05/09/2000

Gender: Male

■ Email address: andre.francavilla20@gmail.com

Website: https://andrefrancavilla.github.io

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/andre-francavilla

• Address: Via Francesco Primaticcio 182, 20147 Milan (Italy)

ABOUT ME

I'm a passionate videogame developer and gamer. I've been playing games ever since I was a child and I've been coding since I was 12 years old. I then became so extremely passionate about game development and programming that I've decided to fulfill my ambitions and take on many opportunities to grow both personally and professionally.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital games developer

Poison Dagger Software (Personal Hobby Team) [2016 – Current]

Videogame Programmer

Raven Travel Studios [01/11/2019 - 01/03/2020]

Address: (Italy)

- Al Programming
- Game Mechanics
- Fundamental Game Mechanics for Extra Content
- Main Game Mechanics for Extra Content
- Refactoring

Game Development Mentor

Freelancing [02/2020 – Current]

- Teaching programming methods and techniques
- Post-Session Guidance
- Exercising and Training Assignments

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

High School Diploma In Computer Science

Istituto Tecnico Industriale Statale "Conte Milano" [15/09/2014 - 08/06/2019]

Address: Polistena (Italy) Level in EQF: EQF level 5

High School Education specialized in Computer Science and Networking

Online Courses

[2014 - Current]

Field(s) of study: Computing

- Self educated in general game development and studied in depth advanced programming techniques
- Game Design
- C# and Unity
- Advanced Animation Implementation (IK systems)
- Optimization

Certificate of Attendence

Digital Bros Game Academy [12/10/2020 - Current]

Address: Via Giovanni Labus, 15/3, 20147 Milan (Italy)

https://www.dbgameacademy.it/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s):

English, Italian

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office / Social Media / Google Drive / Google Docs / Rider IDE / Visual Studio & VS Code IDE / Photoshop / Krita / Unity / C++ / Java / MySQL / CSS / PHP / HTML / JSON / XML / C# / Linux / Github / Fork / GIT (GitHub, GitLab, Bash)

PUBLICATIONS

Publications

When I presented my game at Fantastica, I appeared on strettoweb along with my name and my colleague's name.

(View article).

The game also appeared on Svilupparty's archives. Svilupparty is another event held in Bologna that's dedicated to indie game developers. (View archive entry)

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organisational skills

Q&A Team Management and Workload Assignments

- While working on projects with my personal team
- Kanban Work Organization
 - $\,{}^{\circ}\,$ Skill acquired throughout the years of working both on my own and with others

IOB-RELATED SKILLS

Overview

- Advanced Unity Engine skills (acquired throughout my personal experience and professional education)
- Game Al Programming (whilst working for Raven Travel Studios)
- Multiplayer Game Development and workflow (Academic Training)
- Flawless 2D & 3D project integration (I've worked in all environments, even 2.5D and Pixel Art)
- Implementation and extension of commonly known programming patterns (Singleton, Command, State, ...)
- Creation of custom engine tools to aid the growth of the project's workflow
- Networking (due to CISCO training)

Git

I've been using git for several years. I've used version control in many different scenarios that vary from Game Jams to Production Environments where mistakes can be crucial and teamwork is essential.

You can find my work on GitLab here: https://gitlab.com/andrefrancavilla

Jira, Trello, Hack 'n' Plan

All of my projects are organized using at least one form of issue tracking software. I use Jira for all of the major projects within my team, Trello for all of my mentoring projects, and Hack 'n' Plan for other projects where this software was preferred.

I constantly update and keep track of all of my tasks and, within my hobbyist team, I also am the Project Manager and manage everyone's tasks and deadlines.

During my academic training, all of the projects we have worked on have been managed through some form of issue tracker like Trello or Hack 'n' Plan.

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Gamedev Environment Soft-Skills

The Academy I'm currently attending is a one-year boot camp where multiple projects are created and delivered, simulating a real-world game development environment. I've learned how to communicate efficiently and punctually with my colleagues and team members, and I've learned how to maintain a peaceful work environment in stressful situations.

Communication and interpersonal skills

Excellent communication and pitching skills acquired through promotional events held throughout Italy

OTHER SKILLS

Overview

- Guitar, I've played in a local heavy metal band for a few months
- Music composition for my personal videogames
- Amateur Photography
- 3D Printing DIY
- Arduino
- Web Hosting

PRESENTATIONS

Two Sides of Hell

I've first presented this game at Dave's American Food, situated in Gioia Tauro (RC) when this store had brought a famous Italian YouTuber who gave me permission to present the game on the following date: 16/07/2017.

On this date, I gathered information through an anonymous survey on those who had the chance to play my game, to get an idea of what this project would offer me. The year after, on September 1st, I got the chance to present my game at Fantastica, a trade fair for video games and comic books that has been held at Reggio Calabria.

In 2019, I've presented this game at Svilupparty, a yearly indie game developer event situated in Bologna.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Borsa di Studio a.a 2020/2021

Digital Bros Game Academy [14/10/2020]

The DBGA offers discount fees for their academic year to those who demonstrate the best overall skills.

Best Project - "Pong"

Digital Bros Game Academy [20/11/2020]

This is the first project we tackled during my academic scholarship at DBGA. We were told to recreate Pong with a small twist in near three weeks' time. I and my team won the Best Project award.

Best Tool - Procedural Dungeon Generator

Digital Bros Game Academy [20/04/2021]

Within DBGA, there was a challenge dedicated to Game Programmers where we were given a design document about a procedural dungeon. Each one of us had to create an engine tool to allow designers to create and/or plan procedural dungeons.